真是丢人现眼…
Such a shame...
但我佩服你 威震天
But I applaud you, Megatron.
连驾崩都这么有排场
You certainly made a grand exit.
啊 声波 启动视频会议
Ah Soundwave, cue the audio visual.
我想和士兵们讲两句
I wish to address the troops.
霸天虎大业未竟之际 威震天却突然离世
The loss of Megatron, leader of the great Decepticon uprising
这对我们来说无疑是一个打击
is certainly a blow to our cause.
但我们绝不能因他的悲惨遭遇而感到绝望
Yet we mustn't despair over his tragic... demise.
恰恰相反 我们要对他的壮烈牺牲表示拥护
But instead, embrace his ultimate sacrifice
因为在他的遗体之上
and build upon the foundation he laid
有一个更加强大的身影
with an even mightier hand.
恕我直言 红蜘蛛指挥…呃 红蜘蛛陛下
With all due respect, commander star... er, lord Starscream.
说吧 说吧 什么事？
Yes, yes. What is it?
如果连威震天陛下都没能带领我们征服地球
If we failed to conquer Earth under lord Megatron's command
现在面对那些汽车人 我们还有多少胜算？
what hope do we have now while the Autobots still defend it.
那我就明说了吧
Ahh... Allow me to be crystal clear.
千万年来 我一直站在我们已故主人的身后
I studied for millennia, under our former master.
统领你们绰绰有余
Thus I am equate to lead you.
我 威震天的合法继承人
I, Megatron's true heir
红蜘蛛陛下 破坏大帝！
Lord Starscream, Emperor of Destruction!
这个…
[Murmurs...]
打着我的旗号却毫无斗志的士兵有何用！
What use our troops who can't arise to the task of inflicting unspeakable destruction in my name!
等等…
Hm... But wait
传说有个武艺超群的战士
legend tells of one capable warrior
正巧此人就在这个星球上
one who exists here upon this very planet
应该可以让他唯我是从
one who can be student to my master.
擎天柱 你怎么闷闷不乐？
Optimus, why so glum?
这颗星球…
This planet
甚至所有星球 终于逃出了威震天的魔爪
all planets are finally free from Megatron's tyranny.
我不否认 救护车
I do not disagree, Ratchet.
只是 我比较倾向于改变威震天的意愿
It's just, a small part of me hoped to change Megatron's mind
而不是消灭他的火种
not to extinguish his spark.
擎天柱！那个恶霸的死因不在于你
Optimus, his vileness was not slain by your hand
而是因为他的狂妄自大！
but by his own twisted arrogance.
很抱歉
I'm sorry
我知道你们两个交情很深
I know the two of you have quite a history.
但那个曾和我并肩作战的威震天 很久之前就不在了
But the Megatron whom I once fought beside perished eons ago
一旦成为霸天虎 便不再回头
the day he chose to become a Decepticon.
霸天虎现在可能军心涣散 但他们并非群龙无首
The Decepticons may be in disarray, but they aren't without leadership.
何况红蜘蛛不是威震天
And while Starscream is no Megatron
他从不按常理出牌
he is far from predictable.
霸天虎！
Decepticons!
我们遭到袭击！
We are under attack!
不是袭击 救护车
It's no attack, Ratchet.
是我的火山
It's my volcano.
曾经是
Was.
别动 隔板！
Hold still Bulkhead
木星还少个大红斑
Jupiter needs its red spot.
又洒了
Woopsy.
这…看在火种源的份上 到底在搞什么？！
What... in the Allspark... is going on in here?
我们明天要交作业
Our projects are due tomorrow.
可能还要装一个小东西
Maybe we need one of these doohickeys.
你是摩托车 阿尔茜
You are a motorcycle, Arcee.
你难道不会制造摩托发动机吗？
Shouldn't you know how to build the motorcycle engine?
你还是人类呢 杰克
You're a human, Jack.
你能造出小肠来吗？
Can you build me a small intestine?
只会添乱！
You are... making a mess!
但科学作业在成绩里占的比重很大
But the science affairs are big parts of our grade.
是啊！如果隔板不帮我把太阳系模型弄完…
Yea! If Bulkhead doesn't help me finish this model of our solar system...
隔板怎么会了解你们的太阳系？
Oh? And what does Bulkhead know of your solar system?
大黄蜂见过你们的火山吗？还有…
Or Bumblebee of your volcanoes? Or...
…阿尔茜没见过摩托车吗？
...Arcee of our motorcycles?
说得对！我们不是地球人！
Precisely! We're not earthlings!
他们也不是科学家
And they are not scientists.
但汽车人是他们的守护者 救护车
But the Autobots are their guardians, Ratchet.
帮助我们的年轻朋友完成作业 顺便熟悉地球 何尝不可呢？
Would it hurt to learn more of earth by helping our young friends with their school work?
那…这些年轻朋友也应该熟悉一下塞博特恩
Well... Maybe our young friends should try learning more of Cybertron.
大战期间
During the Great War
这个鬼地方贮藏了许多能量
so much energon was hidden on this forsaken rock
我们的先帝派塞博特恩最棒的战士来守护它们
that our departed master sent some of Cybertron's greatest to guard it.
是真正的勇士 处于沉睡之中
True warriors, now lying in stasis
等待着被唤醒
waiting to be reawakened.
威震天明知道时日不多
Such folly that late in life
还愚蠢地跑到太空深处去寻找战士
Megatron searched distant space for warriors
却忽略了这里 就在他的脚下
rather than here, beneath his feet.
你说无法找到他的信号 是什么意思？
What do you mean you can't pinpoint his signal?
我知道就在附近！
I know we are close!
把你的探测器功率加大！
Boost the power to your sensors!
是的…在那儿…
Yesss... There...
真的吗 大黄蜂？
Really Bumblebee?
那你是怎么进战士班的？
Then how do you make warrior class?
但我看过你打仗 身手不错的！
But I've seen you in action, you are awesome!
我也这么认为 拉夫
I second your opinion, Raf.
但汽车人的生命周期远比人类的要长
But Autobot life cycles are much longer than those of humans.
说起来很难让你信服
And though it may be hard to believe our young scout
但这位年轻的侦察员的确需要累积经验
still has much to experience.
有能量外露 而且正在移动
Exposed energon, and it's on the move.
既然不是我们在动 猜猜会是谁？
And since we ain't moving it, guess who must be?
霸天虎
Decepticons.
威震天不是死了吗？
Without Megatron?
威震天是死了
Unfortunately Megatron's legacy will live on
但恐怕很多人想坐上他的宝座
as others rise to take his place.
汽车人 你们得完成作业
Autobots, you have projects to complete.
救护车 我可能需要帮手
Ratchet, I may require aid.
既然科学作业在他们的成绩里占的比重很大
Science affair is a big part of their grade?
也许我最好留下来 给他们提点建议
Perhaps I'm better suited to remain behind and advise.
好吧
Very well.
大黄蜂 我们去看看这个会飞的能量
Bumblebee, let us see about this energon in transit.
很好 声波
Excellent, Soundwave.
能量块
The cube.
注入的能量
The energon infusion
有效果了！
it's working.
不 大黄蜂 能量不会消失
No Bumblebee, it does not.
坚守岗位 等我的命令
Hold your position, and wait my command.
苏醒吧 战士
Awaken, warrior
醒过来 侍奉你的新主人！
rise and serve your new master.
天震只侍奉一个主人
Skyquake serves only one master.
很好
Excellent
你的忠诚和奉献精神将成为军队的好榜样
your loyalty and devotion will set a fine example for the troops.
不必拘谨 天震
No need to be timid, Skyquake
俯首称臣吧
you may bow.
你没听懂我的话
You failed to grasp my meaning.
派我来这里执行任务的
I am here on a mission
是我唯一的主人 威震天
assigned to me by my one master, Megatron.
对 他嘛…
Yes, him.
很不幸 威震天已经离我们而去了
Sadly Megatron is no longer with us.
不可能！
Impossible.
为什么所有人都难以接受事实？
Why is it so difficult for everyone to accept?
天震 是我把你找到
Skyquake, I located you
是我把你唤醒
I awakened you
所以我 红蜘蛛陛下
thus I, lord  Starscream
现在是你的主人！
am now your master!
好久不见 天震
It has been a while, Skyquake.
擎天柱
Optimus Prime
在泰科纳战役之后我就再没见过你
I haven't seen you since the battle of Technar.
威震天命令我来消灭你
Megatron ordered me to annihilate you.
那都是陈年旧事了
That was a long time ago.
或许是 擎天柱
That may be, Prime.
但命令还是要执行的！
But my order still stand!
这古老的战争还值得打下去吗？
Is this ancient war still worth fighting
那么多同伴悄然离去
when so many comrades have been lost
那么多星球毁于一旦
and worlds destroyed?
如果你想成为一个真正的领袖 红蜘蛛
If you want to be a true leader, Starscream
那就不要走威震天的老路
then stray from Megatron's path
你要带领霸天虎走向和平
and lead the Decepticons toward peace.
我会真心考虑停战的
I would be willing to consider a truce
只要你真心向我称臣 擎天柱
if you would be willing to bow before me, Optimus Prime.
又是称臣？称称这个沉不沉！
Again? Bow to this!
天震 这是一个新时代 一个新世界
Skyquake, this is a new era, on another world
加入汽车人这边 帮我彻底终结这场战争吧！
side with the Autobots and help me end this conflict forever!
我永远不会与你们为伍！
I will never side with a Prime! Ummmaaa...
既然有了天震 我还要和平干嘛？
What need have I for peace when I have Skyquake?
教训他一下
With some discipline
他就会懂得尊敬他的新主人
he will learn to respect his new master.
只要他们知道 天震在我的命令下消灭了擎天柱
And once it becomes known that Skyquake destroyed Optimus Prime under my command
全体霸天虎都会对我心悦诚服！
all Decepticons will gratefully bow to me.
大黄蜂 不！
Bumblebee, no!
一刻也不要漏掉 声波！
Do not miss a single moment, Soundwave!
我们要为擎天柱的辞世拍个纪录片 以儆后人！
We shall need a visual documentation of Optimus Prime's demise, for the historical record.
天震还没有扫描伪装形态
Skyquake has not yet acquired a vehicle mode.
后撤！
Fall back!
年纪越大 胆子越小吗 擎天柱？
So time has made you a coward, Prime?
我看看 在哪呢？
Let's see, where is it?
这是什么？
Em, what is it?
到时候你就知道了
You'll find out.
可是…救护车
But Ratchet
我不是该自己动手吗？
shouldn't I be doing the work?
别动！看着就行了 学着吧
Yi, yap, yap, yap... Don't touch! Just watch. And learn.
那我们去帮杰克和神子完成他们的…
So we'll just go help Jack and Miko finish their...
在我的监督之外？
Without my supervision?
你们也想做到最好吧？
You want them to be right, don't you?
那就欣赏大师的手笔吧！
Then watch a master at work!
控制狂！
Control freak!
他们已经出了视线范围！
We've lost sight of them.
声波 你怎么不去追踪他们？
Soundwave! Why aren't you tracking them!
什么 怎么回事？
What, what is it?
又一个霸天虎的生命信号？
A second Decepticon life signal?
但天震是唯一在这个地区待命的
But Skyquake is the only sleeper buried in this area.
在我们被毁掉的太空桥那里？
The site of our destroyed Space Bridge?
你不是想说
You are not telling me
那个生命信号属于…
that life signal belongs...
…威震天吧？
to Megatron?
可…可他离爆炸点太近了
B, b, b... but he was microns from the detonation point.
没人能在那样的爆炸中生还！
Nothing could have survived that blast!
你的传感器一定有问题！
Your sensors must be faulty.
别理它！
Ignore the contact.
把坐标删除！
Delete the coordinates!
唉 我在说什么呢？
Eh what am I saying?
当然了 去调查一下也无妨
Of course, this must be investigated.
如果真的是威震天陛下
If Lord Megatron is up there
我就去前往迎驾
I shall bring him home.
呆在这里监视情况
Remain here and monitor the outcome.
等天震毁灭擎天柱火种的那一刻
When Skyquake snuffs Prime's spark
我要亲自验证
I must bear witness.
“…要亲自验证”
"...must bear witness."
T6A号呼叫指挥中心
T6A to central command.
我们监测到来自不明物体的信号 可能是敌军
We are picking up transmissions originating from un-identified technology possibly hostile.
我们正前去调查
We are moving to investigate.
不行 T6A！
Negative T6A
我是特工威廉・福勒
this is special agent William Fowler intercepting.
删除你的报告记录
Strike your report from the record
向我提供源坐标
and provide the origin coordinates.
我会去处理的
I'll take it from here.
把你砸扁真是大材小用 小虫子
It will be a shame to crush you, bug
但这是我的职责
but it is my duty.
好计谋 大黄蜂！
Excellent strategy, Bumblebee.
天震 老实趴着吧！
Skyquake, stay down.
福勒？
Fowler?
福勒探员 快撤退！
Agent Fowler, fall back!
这下我算开了眼了
Well, I'll be a bald eagle.
已获得制空权！
Air superiority achieved.
在我的眼皮底下盗取机密军用飞机设计 我决不容忍！
Stealing plans for a classified military aircraft will not be tolerated on my watch!
热能追踪导弹！
Heat seekers!
别想追上我！
I still got it.
没人能在这里生还
No one could have survived this.
如我所料 是传感器故障
Ahh... As I suspected, faulty sensors.
我现在最不想听到的谣言就是 威震天还…
The last thing I need now are rumors that Megatron is still...
威震天…
Megatron...
怎么会这样？
But how?
黑暗能量
Ah, dark energon.
所有人都以为你已经仙逝了
Everyone believes you are deceased.
我怎么忍心让他们失望呢 主人？
Who am I to disappoint them, master?
这一次 永远安息吧！
And this time, stay dead!
声波！你听见了吗？
Soundwave, if you are listening
我找到威震天陛下了
I have found Lord Megatron.
他情况…不太乐观
And he is... unwell.
必须把他送到治疗舱
We must transport him to sick bay
要快！
immediately.
福勒探员 我们请求立刻支援！
Agent Fowler, we require immediate assistance!
不用谢 伙计
Anytime, fellow.
马上要着陆了！
Ground force coming fast!
着陆快乐 虎子
How're the landings, Con?
如果天震没有步他主人的后尘
Had Skyquake chosen to stray from his master's path
我们今天就不会置他于死地了
we might not be burying him today.
大黄蜂 让你孤身冒险也许不算是上策
Bumblebee, putting yourself at risk was perhaps not the wisest of strategies
但你的表现令人钦佩
but you performed admirably.
你们回来了！
there you are.
快说 他们觉得我的 呃…我们的作业怎么样？
Well, how are my, eh, our projects received?
这个嘛…
Well...
仲代小姐 那是哪个星球？
Miss Nakadai, what planet would that be?
嗯…塞博特恩啊
Em, Cybertron?
它…个头不小 达比先生
It's... large, Mr. Darby
可它能运行吗？
but, is it operational?
不知道该不该问 埃斯基维尔先生
I hesitate to ask, Mr. Esquivel
不过…这是活火山吗？
but, eh, is it active?
哼 如果在我们的星球
Well, on our planet
你们会获得最高分的！
you would have been awarded the highest honors.
我就不该参和进来！再也不帮忙了
I get absolutely no credit!  Let's see if I help them.
说得对 大黄蜂
Indeed, Bumblebee
我们的人类朋友不该走上救护车的老路
our human friends would have been wise to stray from Ratchet's path.
知道威震天陛下情况稳定
The troops will be pleased to hear of our success
士兵们一定会很高兴的
in rushing Lord Megatron into stasis.
但愿我们的主人能挺过这一关
Let us hope that our master pulls through.